Sergio R. Hernandez Araujo www.sergiouk10.com sergiouk10@gmail.com mobile 07846009222

Personal Profile

I am a professional with experience in Frontend/Backend Development, Web Design and DevOps. I am dedicated, creative, efficient, and highly focused on finishing projects with high-quality standards. My experience in development is using technologies like React, Sequelize, Express, JavaScript TypeScript, Jest, Nodejs, MySQL, ORM, Responsive Design, Sass, Gulp, PHP, WordPress, Bootstrap, WordPress, HTML, CSS, and more. I also have some involvement designing wireframes, mock-ups, email marketing, good handling of Photoshop and Illustrator with experience in commercial environments and I would like to keep learning more to become in a S.O.L.I.D developer.

Check out digital CV at https://sergiouk10.com

Skills Profile

- React development.
- Handling Redux and usability.
- Experience developing with Sequelize, ORM and MySQL.
- Solid handling express.js.
- Understanding of REST APIs.
- Knowledge of unit test (Jest).
- Development with NextJS.
- GitHub.
- Node.is.
- Docker containers.
- Exposure to GitHub Actions.
- Familiar with Kubernetes.
- Gulp, Sass, pre-processor.
- Jira (project management).
- Work experience in UX design.
- Wireframe builder using Axure.
- High knowledge of Responsive Design.
- Material UI.
- Bootstrap grids and components for responsive design.
- Knowledge of accessibility.
- PHP experience.
- Experience developing WordPress themes (PHP WordPress functions).

Work History

Feb 2018 to Present – Little Star Media Ltd (United Kingdom)

Position: Web Developer

Description: Development, expansion and maintenance of new software created by the team from scratch using React, NextJS and Bootstrap for the Frontend, React, Redux and Material UI for the CMS and Sequelize, Express and Sequelize for the API using JavaScript, TypeScript and Jest for testing

also maintenance of legacy code in PHP using WordPress and additional some exposure to building Docker images, Kubernetes Cluster and deployment to AWS using GitHub Actions.

Oct 2015 to Jun 2017 - AltaVoz S.A. (Chile)

Position: Front-End Designer

Description: Architectural designer of websites and front-end developer of the website projects circle; from building wireframes, mock-ups, code architecture HTML, CSS, JQuery and JavaScript, validation of code and insert the CMS. Another activity was the support to the department of email marketing, validating code HTML and including content.

March 2012 to March 2015 - Imagen Tactica C.A. (Venezuela)

Position: Account Manager

Description: Coordination and execution of advertising projects; from corporate image, outdoor advertising, budget for operations of projects, flyers, business cards, posters, corporate material, and managed effectively the clients through a clear and consistent communication by email, phone and face to face.

Education and Training

- 2011 Bachelor of Corporate Communications, Universidad Santa María. Venezuela
- 2012 Certificate Adobe International HTML, Posa Studio Creativo. Venezuela.
- 2012 Certificate Adobe International Dreamweaver, Posa Studio Creativo. Venezuela.
- 2012 Certificate Adobe International Illustrator CC, Posa Studio Creativo. Venezuela.
- 2012 Certificate Adobe International Photoshop CC, Posa Studio Creativo. Venezuela.

Hobbies

Attending concerts, travelling, surfing, learn about code, workout, to know new places, trekking, listen to good music, cook and a good BBQ.